Guide to the Martin Shubik Papers, 1938-2017 and undated RL.01181
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Martin Shubik papers
1938-2017 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Shubik, Martin
RL.01181
63 Linear Feet
Martin Shubik is Professor Emeritus of Economics and Seymour H. Knox Professor of Mathematical Institutional Economics at Yale University and the Cowles Foundation for Research in Economics. The Martin Shubik Papers span the years 1938 through 2017, and consist of his correspondence, research, writings, and his collaborations and professional affiliations.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The papers of Martin Shubik were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift and as deposits between 1992 and 2021.
Biographical Note
Timeline
1926 Mar. 24 Martin Shubik born in New York, N.Y.
1947 Received B.A. in Mathematics, University of Toronto
1949 M.A., Mathematics, University of Toronto
1951 M.A., Economics, Princeton University
1953 Awarded Ph.D. in Economics, Princeton University
1953-1955 Research Associate, Princeton University
1955-1956 Fellow, Center for Advanced Study, Palo Alto, Ca.
1956-1960 Consultant, General Electric Company
1957-1959 Adjunct Research Professor, Pennsylvania State University
1959 Publication of Strategy and Market Structure
1961-1963 Staff Member, T. J. Watson Research Labs., IBM
1963- Professor of Economics, Seymour H. Knox Professor of Mathematical Institutional Economics, Yale University
1970-1971 Consultant, RAND Corporation
1971 Fellow, Econometric Society
1973-1976 Director, Cowles Foundation, Yale University
1975 Fellow, World Academy of Arts and Sciences
1982 Publication of Game Theory in the Social Sciences
1985 Fellow, American Academy of Arts and Sciences
1999-2010 Publication of The Theory of Money and Financial Institutions, Vols. 1-3
2001 With Paul Bracken, published article titled War Gaming in the Information Age: Theory and Purpose, in the Naval War College Review
2010 Recognized by the American Economic Association as a Distinguished Fellow for his contributions to the field
Collection Overview
The Martin Shubik Papers document his career as an economist. This collection provides an overview of his professional activities, particularly his research and writings on general equilibrium, game theory, the core, oligopoly and market structure, defense and war game analysis, nuclear deterrence, behavior and risk, financial institutions, and money.
The collection also documents his collaborations and communications with prominent economists, including Kenneth Arrow, Gerard Debreu, Milton Friedman, Oskar Morgenstern, John Nash, Paul Samuelson, Herbert Scarf, Lloyd Shapley, and others.
Along with his own scholarship and writings, the collection documents Shubik's time at IBM, his consultancy work for the RAND Corporation, expert witness testimony, his role as a conference organizer and participant, and other professional activities; and his departmental roles, committee work, and teaching contributions at Yale University.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Organized into the following series: Audiovisual Materials, Correspondence, Professional Service, Research and Notes, Writings, Academia, and Personal.
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted; accession 2019-0160 is unprocessed and requires additional arrangement, description, and/or screening. Contact research services for more information.
Economics -- Computer simulation; Economics -- Study and teaching; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Equilibrium (Economics); Financial institutions -- Economic aspects; Game theory; Game theory -- Congresses; Interest; Audiotapes; War -- Mathematical models; Bankruptcy -- Economic aspects; Deterrence (Strategy); Economics, Mathematical; Prices; Morgenstern, Oskar, 1902-1977; Arrow, Kenneth J. (Kenneth Joseph), 1921-2017; Weinberg, Alvin Martin, 1915-; Debreu, Gerard; Shubik, Martin; Yale University. Cowles Foundation for Research in Economics; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009; Nash, John F., 1928-; Rand Corporation; Mas-Colell, Andreu; Shapley, Lloyd S., 1923-; Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006; Scarf, Herbert E.
- Audiovisual materials, 1965, 1971 and undated; 1 box
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains fifteen audio tapes on reels varying in size from 8" to 3", chiefly lectures given by Shubik. Drafts of many of these lectures may be found in the Writings and Research Series. Titles are taken from original labels and notes on containers. Arranged alphabetically by title.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
  - Book review, undated (Box 1)
  - Contents: first day AM, Dr. Shubik! (Box 1)
  - Gaming, lecture, 1965 [TRT: 00:32:00] (Box 1)
  - Gaming conference, tape 2, records, two sides, 15/16, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Gaming conference, tape 3, one side, 15/16, 1971 (architectural sketch on cover) (Box 1)
  - Game theory, Shubik lecture, no. 1, 3/9 (Box 1)
  - Game theory, Shubik lecture, no. 2, 2/16 (Box 1)
  - Tape 1, chapter 5 [and Firestone?], undated (Box 1)
  - Tape from Shubik (at RAND), addressed to Mrs. E. Walker, Yale, 7/23 (Box 1)
  - Transcribe for Prof. Deutsch, tape no. 2, Shubik lecture, undated (Box 1)
  - Transcribe for Prof. Deutsch, tape no. 3, Shubik lecture, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified tape 3, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified tape 6, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified tape 7, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified tape, undated (Box 1)
  - Interview on the History of Experimentation in Economics with Martin Shubik, by Andrej Svorencik, undated (Cd RL-01181-CD-001, Box 1)
  - The Proceedings of the 36th International Simulation and Gaming Association 28 June - 2 July 2005, 2005 June 28-July 2 (Cd RL-01181-CD-002, Box 1)
  - 2nd Annual IB Research Forum Global Risk Management: Financial, Operational and Insurance Strategies, 2001 April 20 (Cd RL-01181-CD-003, Box 1)
  - Martin Shubik: An Economist's Reminiscences, 2005 Feb. 23 (Cd RL-01181-CD-004, Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1947-2016; 1
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains Shubik's correspondence organized by date and alphabetically by last name, preserving Shubik's original organization. Among his most frequent correspondents is his longtime collaborator Lloyd Shapley, as well as other prominent economists, including Kenneth Arrow, Gerard Debreu, Milton Friedman, Oskar Morgenstern, John Nash, Paul Samuelson, and Herbert Scarf, among others. The series also contains Shubik's non-academic correspondence with newspapers, magazines, companies, and museums.
  - Chronological Files, 1947-2014; 1
    This subseries contains Shubik's arranged correspondence, arranged chronologically by year. Correspondence ranges from his early career at IBM to his time at Yale University. Correspondents of note include Kenneth Arrow, Gerard Debreu, Oskar Morgenstern, John Nash, Herbert Scarf, and Lloyd Shapley, among others.
    - 1950s (Box 8)
    - 1947-1967, 3 folders (Box 125)
    - 1960, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - 1960s - 1970s (Box 127)
    - 1961, 1-3 of 4 folders (Box 8)
    - 1961, 4 of 4 folders (Box 9)
    - 1962, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1963, 1 of 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1963, 2 of 2 folders (Box 10)
    - 1964, 4 folders (Box 10)
    - 1965, 1 of 3 folders (Box 10)
    - 1965, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 11)
    - 1966, 4 folders (Box 11)
    - 1967, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - 1968, 1 of 5 folders (Box 12)
    - 1968, 2-5 of 5 folders (Box 13)
    - 1969, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 13)
    - 1969, 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 14)
    - 1970, 1-3 of 4 folders (Box 14)
    - 1970, 4 of 4 folders (Box 15)
    - 1971, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - 1972, 1 of 2 folders (Box 15)
    - 1972, 2 of 2 folders (Box 16)
    - 1973, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - 1974, 4 folders (Box 17)
    - 1975, 1 of 4 folders (Box 17)
    - 1975, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 18)
    - 1976, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box 18)
    - 1976, 3 of 3 folders (Box 19)
    - 1977, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - 1978, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 1979, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 1980s (Box 127)
    - 1980, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - 1981, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - 1982, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - 1983, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 22)
    - 1983, 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 23)
    - 1984, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - 1985, 5 folders (Box 24)
    - 1986 (Box 25)
    - 1987, 1 of 4 folders (Box 25)
    - 1987, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 26)
    - 1988, 1 of 2 folders (Box 26)
    - 1988, 2 of 2 folders (Box 27)
    - 1989, 4 folders (Box 27)
    - 1990s (Box 127)
    - 1990, 4 folders (Box 28)
    - 1991, 3 folders (Box 29)
    - 1992, 1 of 4 folders (Box 29)
    - 1992, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 30)
    - 1993, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - 1994, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - 1995, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - 1996, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - 1997, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - 1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box 32)
    - 1998, 2 of 2 folders (Box 33)
    - 1999, 1-3 of 5 folders (Box 33)
    - 1999, 4-5 of 5 folders (Box 34)
    - 2000s (Box 127)
    - 2000, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - 2001, 4 folders (Box 35)
    - 2002, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - 2003, 1 folder (Box 36)
    - 2004-2009, 1 folder (Box 36)
    - 2005-2014, 2 folders (Box 125)
  - Alphabetical Files, 1961-2016; 2
    This subseries contains Shubik's alphabetically arranged correspondence. Correspondents of note include: Kenneth Arrow, Gerard Debreu, Ralph Gomory, John Nash, and Eric Smith. This subseries also contains Shubik's correspondence with publishers and academic journals.
    - A miscellaneous, 1980s-1990s (Box 36)
    - Advisory Commission of the Division of the Social Sciences, 1980s (Box 36)
    - Aequus Institute, grants, 1990s (Box 36)
    - Alfred Sloan Foundation, 1997 (Box 36)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1999 May (Box 126)
    - American Economic Review, 1960s-1980s (Box 36)
    - Andrew Mas-Colell, 2001 (Box 126)
    - ARPA-related correspondence, 1970s (Box 37)
    - Arrow, Kenneth, 2013 (Box 127)
      Includes discussion of money in general equilibrium theory and economic theory in general
    - Assignment Game from Chang-Zhou Qin, 2015 May (Box 126)
    - Author's permission request by Blaug, Mark, 1999 (Box 51)
    - Barry O'Neill, 1996 (Box 36)
    - Book permission requests for Market Structure and Behavior, 1979 (Box 36)
    - Book, The War Game, 1979-1980 (Box 36)
    - Bracken, Jerome, 1991 (Box 36)
    - Brainware, 1990s (Box 36)
    - Brazil, 1971-1974 (Box 36)
    - Canada Council, 1974-1983 (Box 36)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1994 (Box 36)
    - Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems Research, 1980s (Box 36)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1965-1979 (Box 36)
    - Charles A. Wilson: Book suggestion, 1989 August (Box 126)
    - Charles Goodhart, 2013 (Box 126)
    - Chile, 1965 (Box 37)
    - China, 1993-1994 (Box 37)
    - Commission on the Year 2000, Computer Committee, 1967-1972 (Box 37)
    - Conferences, 1970s (Box 37)
    - Conflict Conference, 1979 (Box 37)
    - Correspondence on Conference on Evaluation of Art of Gaming, RAND, 1971 (Box 37)
    - Cowles Commission budget, 1967-1975 (Box 37)
    - Cowles Lunch Talk, 2012 May; 2016 April (Box 126)
    - Cynthia Erickson, 2006 (Box 126)
    - D miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 37)
    - Decision Models of Strategic Conflict, 1981 (Box 37)
    - Economic notes, Siena, 1997 (Box 37)
    - Econophysics, 2005 (Box 37)
    - Edward Knapp, 1994 Nov. (Box 126)
    - F miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s (Box 37)
    - Fan mail, 1992; 1994 (Box 37)
    - Ferdinand K. Levy, 1991-1994 (Box 126)
    - Finance recruiting, 1970s (Box 37)
    - Ford Foundation, 1986-1990 (Box 37)
    - Game Theory in the Social Sciences, 1980s; 1 of 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Game Theory in the Social Sciences, 1980s; 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Game Theory in the Social Sciences and Game Theory in Economics, 1966-1992 (Box 37)
    - Games for Society, Business and War, 1972-1973 (Box 38)
    - Gary Gorton, 2013 (Box 126)
    - Gerard Debreu: Manuscript suggestion, 1989 (Box 126)
    - Global Alliance for Management Excellence, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Gomory, Ralph E., IBM, 1990 (Box 50)
    - Handbook of Game Theory with Economic Applications, 1990 (Box 38)
    - Harold M. Ickes, undated (Box 126)
    - Harvard University Press, 1970s-1980s (Box 38)
    - Hong Kong, 1994 (Box 38)
    - I miscellaneous correspondence, 1965-1992 (Box 38)
    - Institute for Advanced Studies, 1970-1983 (Box 38)
    - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis, 1977-1984 (Box 38)
    - International Journal of Game Theory, 1970s (Box 38)
    - J miscellaneous correspondence, 1977-1988 (Box 38)
    - Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, California, 1966-1980 (Box 38)
    - John Hattendorf, 1999 (Box 126)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1970s-1980s (Box 38)
    - Journal of Political Economy, 1972-1980 (Box 39)
    - Journals, miscellaneous, 1964-1989 (Box 39)
    - K miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s (Box 39)
    - Kenya (Ford Foundation), 1972-1973 (Box 39)
    - Kluwer Publishers, RISK, 1990s (Box 39)
    - Kumar, 1998 (Box 39)
    - L miscellaneous correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 39)
    - Letters to editors, etc., 1974 (Box 37)
    - Loannis Karatzas, 1995-2002 (Box 126)
    - M miscellaneous correspondence, 1970s-1990s; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - M. Shubik festschrift, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Market Structure and Behavior, 1978-1980 (Box 40)
    - Martin H. Krieger, 1994 (Box 126)
    - Mathematics of Conflict, 1980s (Box 40)
    - Michael Barzelay, 1997 (Box 126)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1989-2010 (Box 126)
    - Morgenstern volume, 1961-1976 (Box 40)
    - Museum Correspondence (1 of 3), 1971-2000 (Box 126)
    - Museum Correspondence (2 of 3), 2000 Aug. - 2001 Jan. (Box 126)
    - Museum Correspondence (3 of 3), 2001 Apr. - 2002 Mar. (Box 126)
    - Museum of Finance, 2002 (Box 126)
    - Museum of Money, 2000 (Box 40)
    - N miscellaneous correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 40)
    - Nash, John, 1990s (Box 40)
    - New York City, 1967 (Box 40)
    - New York subway system, 1966-1967 (Box 40)
    - Newspapers and magazines, 1990-1991 (Box 40)
    - Nobel Prize 2009 Nomination, 2008 (Box 126)
    - O miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s (Box 40)
    - Office of Naval Research, 1960s-1980s; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Old relevant letters, 1962 (Box 40)
    - Operations research, 1967-1968 (Box 40)
    - P miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 40)
    - Per Bak, 1996 (Box 126)
    - PEW repost, 1989-1990 (Box 41)
    - Powers, Michael, 2001 (Box 127)
    - Princeton University Press, 1960s (Box 40)
    - Proposal evaluation, NSF, 1982-1988 (Box 41)
    - Q miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 41)
    - R miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 41)
    - R.D.C.Black, 1990s (Box 126)
    - Recommendation for Tom Quint, 1995-1998 (Box 126)
    - Risks and Financial Instruments, 1990s (Box 43)
    - Ronald G. Bodkin, 1996; 1999 (Box 126)
    - S miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 43)
    - Sachnoff, Weaver, 1988 (Box 43)
    - Schizer, David, 2001 (Box 127)
    - Shubik celebration, 1991; 1 of 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Shubik celebration, 1991; 2 of 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Siena, 1992 (Box 44)
    - Smith, Eric, 2012-2015 (Box 127)
      Includes corespondence related to co-authored work
    - Social Systems, 1979 (Box 44)
    - Stony Brook, 1985 (Box 44)
    - Submissions, 1970s (Box 44)
    - Submissions, 1990s (Box 44)
    - Submissions and talks, 1970s (Box 44)
    - T miscellaneous correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 44)
    - TEAS Program, 1961 (Box 44)
    - The Journal of Conflict Resolution, 1960s (Box 38)
    - The Journal of Economic Education, 2008 (Box 126)
    - The MIT Press, 1993-2000 (Box 126)
      Includes correspondence related to book endorsements and reviews
    - The RAND Corporation, 1960s-1970s; 1-4 of 5 folders (Box 41)
    - The RAND Corporation, 1970s; 5 of 5 folders (Box 40)
    - The War Game, 1972-1978; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Theory of Money and Financial Institutions, 1980s-1990s (Box 44)
    - To Kenneth J. Arrow, 1972 (Box 126)
    - U miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 44)
    - Universite du Quebec A Montreal, 1992-1993 (Box 126)
    - V miscellaneous correspondence, 1980s (Box 44)
    - W miscellaneous correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 44)
    - Whitman, Martin, 1970-1971 (Box 127)
    - Williams College, 1988-1989 (Box 44)
    - Yale information, 1980s (Box 45)
    - Yale inter-office correspondence, 1970s (Box 45)
    - Yale University Press, 1970s-1990s (Box 45)
- Professional Service, 1956-2014; undated; 1
  This series documents Shubik's professional activities. These include: conference and workshop presentations; conferences and workshops organized by Shubik; files related to service with professional organizations; consulting for various companies and organizations; and expert witness testimony.
  - Conferences and Organizations, 1957-2014; undated; 1
    This subseries contains alphabetically arranged files related to Shubik's participation in and organization of various conferences and workshops, as well as his involvement in professional organizations. Also included are grant proposals, and files for his work to establish a Museum of Money.
    - 10th International Conference on Cultural Economics, Barcelona, 1998 (Box 121)
    - 50th Anniversary of The Theory of Games and Economic Behavior, Barcelona, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Aequs grant, (correspondence), 1991-2000s (Box 51)
    - Agenda of America Conference, 1975 (Box 3)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1996-1999 (Box 127)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, call for nominations, 1992 (Box 51)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Commission of the Year, 2000 (Box 52)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, nominations correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 51)
    - American Statistical Association, list of committees, etc., 1961 (Box 46)
    - An Exploratorium and Museum of Money and Financial Institutions, 1999 (Box 51)
    - Annual Meeting of Bios Fellows, Santa Fe, 1999 (Box 51)
    - Atoms, Individuals, Instruments; The Evolution of Money and Financial Institutions, undated (Box 121)
    - Balinski, Stony Brook, 1984 (Box 49)
    - Barcelona Conference on Museums, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Biology and Economics Conference, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Biology, Information, Andrew Marshall, Virginia, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Bioterrorism project, 2000s (Box 121)
    - Center for Applied Mathematics lectures, 1973 (Box 122)
    - Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems Research, grant proposals etc., 1982 (Box 49)
    - Center for War Gaming, 1971 (Box 48)
    - China CCTV Documentary on Money, undated (Box 125)
    - Colloquium series, Santa Fe Institute, Three Lectures on The Theory of Money and Financial Institutions, undated (Box 7)
    - Computational Philosophy Lessons from Simple Models, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Conference Auctions and Biddings: Uses and Theory, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Conference Defense and Deterrence: Economics, History and Political Science Approaches, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Conference on Biology, Information and the Future of National Security, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Conference on Coping with Financial Instability, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Conference on Learning, Rationality and Games, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Conference on Managing International Risk, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Conference on Mathematical Models of Conflict and Combat: Uses and Theory, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Conference on Models, Simulations and Games, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Conference on Peace, Defense and Economic Analysis, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Conference on Politics of Corporate Planning and Modeling, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Conference on Research and Technology, Office of Naval Research, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Conference on Simulations of a Business, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Conference on the Future Impact of Computers, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Conference on The History of Game Theory, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Conference on The Micro-economic Foundation of Macro-economics, Spain, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Conference on Themes in Economics, Celebration of I. Fisher, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Conference The Future of the World's Financial Institutions, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Conference The Global Economy as a Complex Adaptive System, Santa Fe, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Conference The Information Revolution and International Security, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Conference, Incomplete Markets and Strategic Market Games, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Conference, Missing Financial Markets, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Conference, New Horizons in Search Theory: From Abstraction to Application, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Conferences, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Conferences, 1960-1985 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1975-1979 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, 1983-1990 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
    - Conferences, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
    - Conferences and Invitations, 1989-1991 (Box 5)
    - Conferences on Naval Technology, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Conferences on Takeovers and Contests for Corporate Control, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Consortium research proposal, Laboratory Research Consortium for Controlled Experimentation in the Social and Behavioral Sciences, 1976 (Box 48)
    - Cowles Foundation Lunch Seminar, Money, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Cowles Lunch Talk, "Reminiscences" of Shubik, undated (Box 7)
    - Decision Analysis Group at Stanford Research Institute, presentation of models and their methodologies, 1975 (Box 48)
    - Decision Sciences Colloquium, Gus Stuart, Harvard University, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
    - Department of Economics at Ben-Gurion University, 2011 (Box 126)
    - Department of Economics, UCLA, 1993 (Box 126)
    - Department of Economics, University of Bonn, July 2000-Jan 2002 (Box 126)
    - Distinguished Lecture Series at The University of Southern California, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Draft for Wilton Park Presentation, Utgott, Victor A., 1993 (Box 6)
    - Economic Notes Conference, Siena, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Economic Science Association, 1987 (Box 49)
    - Economic Theory and Future: Economics, Physics, and Biology, Santa Fe, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Economics and Operations Research, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Economics Seminar, UNM Economics Department on A Game-Theoretic Approach to the Theory of Money, 2006 (Box 7)
    - El Periodico de la Universidad, undated (Box 52)
    - Experimentation in the Social Sciences - Stony Brook Conference, 2012 (Box 127)
      Includes presentation
    - Exploratorium proposals and correspondence, 1991-2000s (Box 122)
    - Faculty Seminar, undated (Box 126)
    - Financial Expert Conference, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Financing of a Public Good by Taxation in a General Equilibrium Economy: Theory and Experimental Evidence, 2011; undated (Box 125)
    - Fire Support Methodology Workshop, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Fourth International Workshop on Game Theory, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Fred Roberts, 1980s (Box 50)
      Includes draft proposal to the Mellon Fund and other related documents
    - Game Theory Workshop trip report, undated (Box 7)
    - Gaming Conference, 1971-1974; 8 folders (Box 4)
      CHECK
    - General Electric, 1957 (Box 127)
      Includes documents from work done at General Electric
    - Grant application, Study of Defense Implications, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Grant for Museum of Money and Financial Institutions, 1999; 2001 (Box 126)
    - Grant paperwork, 1985-1987 (Box 49)
    - Grant proposal, 1988 (Box 49)
    - Grant proposal, Strategic Planning and Risk Analyses, 1984 (Box 49)
    - Guggenheim Forum Program, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Guggenheim Museum, 1988 (Box 49)
      Memo related to serving on foundation board